Sangwon Seo

Research Objectives

My research focuses on *Generative Models of Human Behavior*, *Human-Robot Collaboration*, and *AI-Assisted Decision Making*. During my PhD, I developed *imitation/reinforcement learning* algorithms capable of learning generalized agent policies from diverse human behaviors, as well as an *AI-driven team coaching system* that automatically analyzes and enhances teamwork in real time.

Education

Rice University, Houston, TX

Aug 2019 – Present

Ph.D. in Computer Science

• Thesis (Tentative): AI-Assisted Teamwork

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2013 – Feb 2015

M.S in Bioengineering

• Thesis: Performance Enhancement in Heart Rate Variability Analysis with Constrained Missing RR Interval Estimation

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2009 – Feb 2013

B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Thesis: Multiplexing of Bead-Based Immunoassays using a BioMEMS

Experience _____

Honda Research Institute USA, San Jose, CA

May 2024 - Aug 2024

Research Intern

- Job Description: Human behavior modeling and optimization for human-aware automation
- Developed mathematical models to capture changes in human propensities for interacting with other agents and learned these models from demonstrations.
- Inferred individual interaction propensities with other agents from observable states and actions using sequential Monte Carlo methods

Human-Centered AI and Robotics Group, Rice University, Houston, TX Ph.D. Candidate (Advisor: Prof. Vaibhay Unhelkar)

Aug 2020 – Present

- Ph.D. Candidate (Advisor: Prof. Vaibhav Unhelkar)
 Proposed a team coaching AI algorithm to improve teamwork in real time during tasks
- Developed sample- and label-efficient imitation learning algorithms to learn a generative model of team behavior
- Developed a hierarchical imitation learning algorithm to learn the intentional behavior of experts from demonstrations
- Implemented multiple teamwork simulators and research tools
- Implemented a web-based interactive experiment framework and conducted human subject experiments

Coreline Soft, Seoul, South Korea

Apr 2016 – Jun 2019

Associate Research Engineer

- Responsible for developing algorithms for AVIEW MODELER, a medical 3D printing solution
- Developed geometric modeling and processing algorithms
- Implemented a volume and surface rendering pipeline

Agency for Defense Development, Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2015 - Mar 2016

Researcher

• Developed a telemetry system for aircraft

Biomedical Signal and Information Lab, Seoul National University M.S Student (Advisor: Prof. Kwang Suk Park)

Feb 2013 - Feb 2015

- Developed signal/image processing algorithms for daily monitoring of physiological signals
- Developed autoregressive moving average-based interpolation methods to enhance heart rate variability analysis corrupted with missing measurements

Publications

- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "IDIL: Imitation Learning of Intent-Driven Expert Behavior", 23nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2024 (Acceptance rate 25%)
- S. Seo, "AI-Assisted Human Teamwork", AAAI-24 Doctoral Consortium, 2024
- S. Seo, B. Han and V. V. Unhelkar, "Automated Task-Time Interventions to Improve Teamwork using Imitation Learning", 22nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2023 (Acceptance rate 23.3%)
- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "Semi-Supervised Imitation Learning of Team Policies from Suboptimal Demonstrations", *31st International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2022 (Acceptance rate 14.9%)
- **S. Seo**, L. R. Kennedy-Metz, M. A. Zenati, J. A. Shah, R. D. Dias and V. V. Unhelkar, "Towards an AI coach to infer team mental model alignment in healthcare", *2021 IEEE Conference on Cognitive and Computational Aspects of Situation Management (CogSIMA)*, pp. 39-44, 2021
- S. Kwon, D. Lee, J. Kim, Y. Lee, S. Kang, **S. Seo** and K. Park, "Sinabro: A smartphone-integrated opportunistic electrocardiogram monitoring system", *Sensors*, 16(3), p.361, 2016
- S. H. Hwang, S. Seo, H. N. Yoon, H. J. Baek, J. Cho, J. W. Choi, Y. J. Lee, D.-U. Jeong and K. Park, "Sleep period time estimation based on electrodermal activity", *IEEE journal of biomedical and health informatics (J-BHI)*, 21(1), pp.115-122, 2015
- S. Kang, S. Kwon, C. Yoo, S. Seo, K. Park, J. Song and Y. Lee, "Sinabro: Opportunistic and unobtrusive mobile electrocardiogram monitoring system", 15th Workshop on Mobile Computing Systems and Applications (HotMobile), pp. 1-6, 2014
- J. Kim, S. Kwon, **S. Seo** and K. Park, "Highly wearable galvanic skin response sensor using flexible and conductive polymer foam", *36th annual international conference of the IEEE engineering in medicine and biology society (EMBC)*, pp. 6631-6634, 2014

Working / Under-review Papers

- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "Imitation Learning of Diverse Team Behavior from Heterogeneous Demonstrations", *Under Review*
- **S. Seo**, B. Han, R. E. Harari, R. D. Dias, M. A. Zenati, E. Salas and V. V. Unhelkar, "Socratic: Enhancing Human Teamwork via AI-enabled Coaching", *Under Review*
- Z. Qian, S. Seo, and V. V. Unhelkar, "Learning Human Preferences for Agent Behavior using Demonstrations and Large Language Models"

Honors & Awards

^{*} My employment at the Agency for Defense Development and Coreline Soft is recognized as fulfilling the military service in South Korea.

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant

COMP 646: Deep Learning for Vision and Language (Prof. Vicente Ordóñez-Román) Spring 2023 COMP 440/557: Artificial Intelligence (Prof. Devika Subramanian) Fall 2021

Advising & Mentoring

Arnav Adhikari, Highschool Student, Houston, TXMay 2023 - Dec 2023Bing (Tim) Han, Undergraduate Student, Rice UniversityMay 2022 - May 2024Zhanyi Sun, Undergraduate Student, Rice UniversityJan 2022 - Jun 2022

Reviewer

International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS) International Conference on Advanced Robotics and Its Social Impacts (ARSO) Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L) International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Python | C | C++ | Javascript | HTML | Matlab

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES OpenGL | Flask | PyBullet | PyTorch | Tensorflow

Git | Docker | CMake | Shell Script | VSCode | Jupyter

ROBOT DEVELOPMENT Motion Capture (OptiTrack) | ROS | MoveIt | OMPL

LANGUAGES English | Korean

Extra ____

AAMAS Student Volunteer

Student Venture Network, Seoul National University

College of Engineering Tennis Club, Seoul National University

Mar 2012 – July 2012

Mar 2010 – Feb 2013

System Administrator, ECE Department, Seoul National University

Mar 2010 – Feb 2011

SNU Mentoring, Seoul National University

Sep 2009 – Feb 2010